Curtis J. Jochen

curtis.jochen@gmail.com · 406-471-1679 Richmond, VA 23233

Summary

Young motivated hard-working professional, eager to learn and grow as a developer. 4 years experience managing teams in high intensity large scale projects. Able to hit customer required deadlines efficiently and consistently, often coming in ahead of schedule. Excel at communicating the needs of the customer to that of the team for efficient workflow and completion of day to day tasks. Self-driven and reliable for completion of projects with out continuous need of supervision.

Education

University of Richmond Full Stack Bootcamp Richmond, VA

May 2019 – Oct 2019

Full Stack Certificate Program

Flathead Valley Community College Kalispell, MT

Sept 2012 - Dec 2014

Completed Non-Destructive Testing Trade School

Classroom Training in 5 methods of NDE

Work History

Applied Technical Services

Richmond, VA

Jan 2015 - Present

NDT Technician

- Managing short- and long-term projects on a strict deadline and budget
- Directly leading teams of 10+ people
- Trusted and relied on to solve complex issues under pressure using team members' skills and available resources

Best Buy Kalispell, MT

Nov 2013 – Nov2014

Mobile Sales Rep

- Communicating to gain an understanding of customers needs to help them find the best solution
- Helping resolve customer complaints
- Working through customer's different technical issues while also teaching them how to solve the issue themselves

Montana Fire Eureka, MT

May 2013- Nov 2013

Wildland Firefighter (Seasonal)

- Working with my Crew Boss and team to safely suppress wildfires
- Being aware in a constantly changing and dangerous environment
- Actively helping and supporting team members as needed to achieve our daily and overall objectives

Skills

- Leading and managing teams through highly stressful, production driven environments
- Lots of experience in changing fluid environments and able to learn new skills quickly
- Good interpersonal skills and ability to easily work with a team
- Proficient in Microsoft Office computer platforms
- Strong work ethic and ability to be self-motivated to complete tasks
- Working in ambiguous setting effectively

Volunteer Work

Coaching Youth Hockey

- Instructed and developed leadership qualities
- Taught fundamental and complex team systems related to the sport of hockey

Bigfork Cave Club

- Cave Conservation
- National Park research and advising

4-H

- Community service
- Raising and training livestock for sale